Guide to the Spy Hop Productions independent film collection 2000-2009
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 53)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    A group of young woman talks to the camera
    Interview with a man and three young boys (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a man in a blue parka (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young boy in an Olympic baseball cap (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a woman in a brown turtleneck sweater (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a man in a blue polo shirt and an woman in a red sweater (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with two women volunteers wearing "Host City" volunteer smocks (sound corrupted, no sound)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 54)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Event parking sign on a busy road
    People mover trolley stopped at a light
    Exterior, Caputos, corner of 300 South and 100 West
    Special Event Parking sign
    "A Grand Welcome" Grand America Hotel billboard
    Coca-Cola jumbotron billboard
    Helicopter in the sky
    Budweiser world party entrance
    People waiting in line for figure skating event
    Zoom out on a sign of an aborted fetus on a pro-life picket sign]
    Man holding a sign which reads "Should God Bless America"
    Pedestrians mill around in a closed parking lot with the Delta Center in the background
    Interview with the man holding a sign which reads "Should God Bless America", pro choice demonstrator (sound corrupted, background noise interference)
    Pedestrians walk around on sidewalks near the Gateway
    A man holds a sign which reads "Planned Parenthood, Marie Stopes MURDERS!"
    Side of a German Television van, 2DF
    Pedestrians cross a street, night
    Parking sign, day
    Interview with a woman on the street in a blue turtleneck and a black jacket (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Display of Peace with the word "Peace" written in several different languages (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a man in a blue and purple fleece coat (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A woman in a gray parka reads to a group of people (sound corrupted, no sound)
    People in the group read small statements typed on strips of paper (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A policeman approaches the group and asks them to clear the sidewalk where they are holding their demonstration in front of the Salt Lake County courthouse (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A large group of people line up on a sidewalk to enter an event, night
    People holding "Trust Jesus" signs stand among a crowd listening to a rock band performing in a square
    Window display for National Wildlands in a building front, people watch television screen in the display
    Interview with a group of girls, night (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young couple, Salt Lake LDS Temple in background (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a group of young people, Trax trolley in background (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Group of young men playing guitars and singing (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    People hold "Trust Jesus" signs with the back side of one of the signs listing a variety of sins (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A young man plays the cello on a street corner (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Men holding small US and French flags walk down a sidewalk, night
    A large group of people sit around an event tent listening to rap performers (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    People walk around outside of event tents, hay strewn on the ground, night (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with two women (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A young woman performs a hula-hoop act with a large hula-hoop around her neck (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Fire jugglers perform in a square (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a group of young women in straw cowboy hats (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with three young women among a group of young adults drinking alcohol (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with three women about their experience in Salt Lake City and at the Olympic Games (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Interview with two local women about their experiences with the Olympic Games in town
    A drum band performs in a square as people watch fire jugglers
    Police in yellow parkas stand on a street corner in a crowd (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    A young man dances in front of the camera (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    A young man in kakis and a black pullover fleece break dances
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 55)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Skyline of Salt Lake Valley at dusk (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Olympic Caldron, long shot (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Soft focus pan of the Salt Lake City skyline at dusk (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Fireworks explode over the Rice-Eccles stadium for either the Closing Ceremonies (sound corrupted, no sound)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 56)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Rice-Eccles Stadium, exterior, dusk
    Fast moving clouds far above Rice-Eccles stadium, dusk
    Olympic Caldron, medium shot
    Rice-Eccles Stadium, exterior, night
    Spotlights shine from Rice-Eccles Stadium, night
    Olympic Caldron, Rice-Eccles Stadium, night
    Fireworks explode over Rice-Eccles Stadium in the Closing Ceremonies, night
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 57)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Interview with David Ferguson and Noelle Lewin with the Utah AIDs Foundation about their involvement with the Olympic Games as volunteers (sound corrupted, partial sound, popping, and distortion)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 58)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Interview with John Selfridge, a social worker working with the homeless during the Olympics
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 59)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Interview with the Saint Provo girl, Alice Liepnieks, for Squatters and Wasatch breweries about her role in the Olympics, alcohol during the Olympics, etc.
    Various shots of downtown Salt Lake City skyscrapers with Olympic building photos of skiers, snowboarders, and ice skaters on them.
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 60)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Airport time lapse footage from above the east escalators in Terminal 1, interior
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 61)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Olympic Caldron, Rice-Eccles Stadium exterior, dusk
    Helicopter, dusk
    Olympic volunteers in blue parkas wait to enter the field of Rice-Eccles stadium for the Closing Ceremonies, dusk
    Long shot, Rice-Eccles Stadium field before the Closing Olympic Ceremonies, dusk
    Olympic Caldron, medium shot, dusk
    Olympic Caldron, long shot, dusk
    View of Rice-Eccles stadium field from high in the bleachers before the start of the Olympic Closing Ceremonies, dusk
    Zoom out from large picture of Olympic Torch bearer to the crowd awaiting the start of the Olympic Closing Ceremonies, dusk
    Zoom out from national flags displayed in front of the Olympic Caldron, dusk
    Cameraman makes adjustment to television camera before the start of the Olympic Closing Ceremonies, dusk
    Sunset from Rice-Eccles Stadium
    Shot of pedestrians in the parking lot of Rice-Eccles Stadium
    Zoom out of the State Capitol Building from Rice-Eccles Stadium, dusk
    Television cameraman positions camera before the start of the Olympic Closing Ceremonies, dusk
    People walk around Rice-Eccles Stadium corridor before the start of the Olympic Closing Ceremonies, dusk
    View from above of volunteers in blue parkas waiting outside of Rice-Eccles Stadium for the start of the Olympic Closing Ceremonies, dusk
    Two volunteers in blue parkas carry large white spheres before the start of the Olympic Closing Ceremonies outside of Rice-Eccles Stadium, dusk
    View of large white spheres stacked by white tents to be used by performers in the Olympic Closing Ceremonies at Rice-Eccles Stadium before the Ceremonies, dusk
    Olympic Performers/volunteers waiting for the start of the Olympic Closing Ceremonies at Rice-Eccles Stadium, dusk
    Various perspective shots of the Olympic Caldron at Rice-Eccles Stadium before the start of the Olympic Closing Ceremonies, dusk
    Various shots of white tents and white spheres to be used in the Closing Ceremonies, dusk
    Tech working in a harness from some scaffolding at Rice-Eccles Stadium before the start of the Olympic Closing Ceremonies
    Sunset on Salt Lake City from Press Box of Rice-Eccles Stadium
    Start of the Olympic Closing Ceremonies
    Athletes from the various nations enter the stadium to take their
    seats
    Fireworks over the stadium
    Singing of the United States National Anthem
    Moby performs while Olympic athletes are invited to dance on the field
    Bon Jovi performs ("Do You Want to Live Forever?") while Olympic Athletes dance on the field
    Salt Lake 2002 Olympic Theme song plays while fireworks go off in background
    Athletes stand at their places in the stands with national flags and the Olympic Caldron in background as the Salt Lake 2002 Olympic Theme song plays
    Bon Jovi performs ("Shot Through the Heart") while Olympic Athletes dance on the field
    Athletes walk around the field taking pictures and talking to one another
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 62)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Pedestrians stand on the sidewalk outside the grounds of the Salt Lake City and County Building
    Downtown parking lot
    Pedestrian crossing sign at a traffic light
    Salt Lake 2002 logo on a street light
    Canadian Hockey fans carry a Canadian flag down a downtown street
    Giant Norwegian flag draped over a building serving as the Norwegian Olympic House
    Tomax Iceland House banner draped on a building serving as the Icelandic Olympic House
    Pedestrians cross the street at the corner of 300 South and West Temple
    View of a white event tent from a moving vehicle
    Salt Lake Olympic Square sign, North gate
    Mural on the side of a building
    Bud Light beer billboard
    Thuringian, Germany tourist house sign posted on an iron gate
    Interview with Peter W. Muller, a coordinator for Thuringian, Germany house working to promote tourism for that area of the country.
    Interview with Gerald working with a German television company to promote tourism for Germany while at the Olympics.
    A couple goes through a cafeteria-style line for authentic German cuisine (sound corrupted, no sound).
    German beer in beverage fridges (sound corrupted, no sound).
    Raw sausages placed on an industrial baking sheet (sound corrupted, no sound).
    Sausages being grilled on a large barbeque grill (sound corrupted, no sound).
    Pastries and other baked goods
    France cultural house sign
    Interview with a man from Paris, France working in the France Cultural House which serves French cuisine. Interview includes his involvement in the Olympics, his impressions of the LDS church in Utah, and the Olympic experience.
    Super long shot of Olympic Caldron, night.
    Tiny lights used to make the Olympic Rings, night.
    Police cars with lights flashing creating a barricade on a side street, view from a tall building, night.
    Long shot, LDS Salt Lake City Temple, day.
    State Liquor Store, exterior, day.
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 63)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Torch Relay Party:
    People stand on a street corner
    A man in a cowboy hat greets crowd over microphone
    Police vehicles escort a group of torch relay vehicles, on is a Chevy truck with a small Olympic caldron of fire in the truck bed.
    A man in white torch barer tracksuit waits to do his run, day.
    Interview with a "mountain men" in buckskin clothing about the mountain men exhibit at the Salt Lake Olympic Square and their impressions of Utah and the Olympics, day.
    Interview with Chris Edmonds (woman) and Jim Wangston who are part of the "mountain men" exhibit at the Salt Lake Olympic Square and their involvement in the Olympics, day.
    Interview with Jeff Inengesbauh about his involvement as a mountain man at the Salt Lake Olympics, day.
    Pan across the Mountain Man exhibit, day
    Wells Fargo stagecoach, day
    Riot outfitted police officers stand in a blocked off street in downtown Salt Lake, night.
    A large group of intoxicated people harass police officers in a blocked off street, downtown Salt Lake, night.
    Helicopter overhead, night.
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 64)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Children stand around holding various national flags (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A large group of children in various national costumes sing for an audience (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Tape corrupted
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 65)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Interview with Matu Finau (sound corrupted, low sound levels)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 66)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    A group of teen boys with skateboards stand on a wooden platform next to a Penske rental truck.
    Close up of Budweiser Beer sign which reads: Buzz in for a Budweiser at the Busy Bee
    View of residential Salt Lake area from a moving vehicle
    This Is The Place Heritage Park gate entrance
    This Is The Place monument (Extreme long shot)
    This Is The Place monument (Long shot)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 67)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Time lapse downtown Salt Lake City, (recognizable buildings: Grand America Hotel, Wells Fargo Building, BankOne Building, Red Lion Hotel), sun setting.
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 68)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Photo of historic Palmyra, NY printing press where the first pages of the Book of Mormon were printed
    Lithograph of Joseph Smith
    Lithograph of Joseph Smith recieving the Golden Plates from the Angel Moroni
    Picture of Brigham Young
    Picture of pioneers headed toward the Salt Lake Valley
    Picture of pioneers
    Picture of Greek Orthodox members
    Picture of miners from the 1800s
    Picture of miners with mules
    Picture with a group of men on a locomotive
    Picture of a locomotive in snow
    Picture of a group of men in prision uniforms from the 1800s
    Picture of a large group of women from the mid to late 1800s
    City plan of Salt Lake from the 1800s
    Picture of LDS Salt Lake Temple
    Pictures of two men (Frederick H. Auerbach and Samurel H. Auerbach) with the caption "Founders 1864" beneath them
- Claymation shorts and Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary newspaper footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 69)
  - Claymation sound effects (various), 2002 (Video 1)
  - "The Horse That Laid An Egg" - claymation, 2002 (Video 2)
    A horse lays an egg and leaves it in a nest. Dinosaurs handle the egg until it hatches and the horse comes back.
  - "Splat! Ooof!" - claymation, 2002 (Video 3)
    A tree-vine-swinging man smashes into a tree and falls to the ground only to have a chimp throw a coconut on his head.
  - Untitled claymation, 2002 (Video 4)
    Nefarious characters murder a man only to die in painful ways themselves.
  - "Game Over!" - claymation, 2002 (Video 5)
    A man plays a videogame only to have his television set turn into a monster and eats him.
  - "Dude's New Do" - claymation, 2002 (Video 6)
    A visit to the barber for a new hairstyle convinces a man in the end to go with his usual 'do' after all.
  - "Trendy" - claymation, 2002 (Video 7)
    A teen spray paints on a brick wall. When confronted by another teen, he beats him up and steals his wallet.
  - Olympics newspaper footage, 2002 (Video 7)
    Olympics newspaper footage:
    Articles Entitled:
    "Defending the Home Front"
    "Rodeo Protestors Claim 'Hassling' on Torch-Run Route"
    "Salt Lake Olympic Committee (SLOC) Offers Refunds to Oly Ticket Holders"
    "Olympic Games Spotlights Beauty, Dynamism of Utah"
    "The BIGGEST Show Bar None - 'Light of the World' will shine on an audience of 200,000"
    "Companies Jump On Olympic Bandwagon to Push Products"
    "Ticket Giveaway Turns Unruly"
    "Visiting Oly Athletes Give Cache Valley Games Fever"
    "City Taking on an International Flavor"
    "Crowd Gets Unruly at Ticket Sites"
    "Mountains and Snow - Scandal and Mormons"
    "Image Conscious - Admitting the problem is step No. 1 as ill-at-ease Utah takes world stage"
    "Caldron Builder Goes Bankrupt"
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 70)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    A reporter speaks to the camera in a Pacific Island language in front of the Salt Lake City and County Building and several of the designated areas for cultural events.
    Reporter interviews various individuals working at the Mountain Man exhibit. (sound corrupted, low sound levels)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 71)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Interview with Joyce Anderson who worked as project coordinator for the Olympics, working in Humanitarian Sector and dealing in particular with the homeless housing situation during the Olympics.
    Interview with Andrea Picketts who works in the Office of Human Relations for the city of Salt Lake. Picketts worked with the Humanitarian Sector of the Olympic committee during the preparation for the Olympics.
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 72)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Bobsled finals.
    US beats Latvia.
    Shots of the crowd and traffic at the bobsled event.
    Interview with Arace Dodson who is riding the free transportation on the last day of the Olympics for the fun of it.
    View from a free shuttle.
    A police officer escorts a man and a woman in handcuffs away down a street.
    View from a vehicle during a stand-still traffic jam.
    View from a stopped vehicle of pedestrians at crosswalk.
    View of 300 South from a vehicle, day.
    "Welcome to Salt Lake City" Budweiser sign hanging over Olive Garden Resturant
    Lambs Grill Resturant exterior
    Interview with Amanda Pena (spelling?), who works as a security guard at the Gateway Mall. Interview about changes made for the Olympics.
    Footage of downtown Arts Plaza
    Zoom out on a pile of temporary fencing stacked by a paring lot.
    Long shot, people work on cables outside of the Delta Center.
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 73)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    NBC news crew sets up lights and camera for a night shoot in Park City
    Interview with a young man, Howard, from Norway who loves the Olympics but doesn't like Utah because "there are too many liquer laws and Mormons."
    Park City, night.
    United States flag, night.
    Cresent moon, night.
    Coca-Cola Polar Bear takes pictures with people and dances.
    Monster.com monster statue in a busy Park City street.
    Woman wearing a jacket with the Olympic seal on it.
    A man shouts messages about Jesus and the Bible to pedestrians through a megaphone.
    Norweigans in a crowd chant something over and over again in their native language.
    Kids walk around in odd Olympic coats at an Olympic clothing display.
    Interview with a Canadian man, Harvey Brimmer, about his visit to Utah and the Olympics.
    Interview with two Polish men visiting Utah for the first time, their impressions about the state and the Olympics.
    Interview with a woman from New York wearing a foam Statue of Liberty crown, Penny Mosson, about her visit to Utah and her opinions about the Olympics, particularly about the ice skating scandal involving the Canadian pair gold medal scandal.
    Interview with a guy, Spike, selling hot dogs in Park City at the Olympics.
    Border Patrol sport utility vehicle (SUV).
    People buying water and food from Spike, the hot dog vendor.
    People walking down Main Street in Park City.
    Park City TV interview with Jeddidiah Smith (Steve) a mountain man character who supposedly has lived in Park City for 150 years.
    Park City TV reporter stands with a group of Swedes as they sing "We beat Canada, tra-la-la-la-la"
    Fireworks explode over Park City as people watch and cheer and a song plays over speakers.
    People stand by a fire barrel getting warm as a band plays in the background.
    The Swedes from the TV interview pose in a picture with a woman from the US.
    No Name Saloon sign.
    People drink in the No Name Saloon.
    People stand on the street talking.
    Canadian figure skaters are presented with their gold medal in a televised presentation broadcast over a jumbotron in the street in Park City.
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 74)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" from stage left (Video 1)
    A Polynesian (from Tonga) marching/dance band from the Free Weslyan Church of Tonga performs a number on the Medals Plaza stage.
    A young girl performs a dance on the Medals Plaza stage as a the marching band claps and another group plays instruments and sings for her.
    Polynesian marching/dance band performs a number on the Medals Plaza stage.
    A group of girls performs a dance on the Medals Plaza stage as a the marching band claps and another group plays instruments and sings for her.
    Band plays as a man sings (perhaps a national anthem) on the Medals Plaza stage.
    Band plays as a large group of people sing on the Medals Plaza stage.